paydayuk.co.uk 2016-10-25

# Privacy Policy | PaydayUK

PaydayUK is a trading name of Instant Cash Loans Limited. We are registered in England and Wales under company number 681750 and we have our registered office at 6 Bevis Marks, London, EC3A 7BA. Data Protection registration number Z6250344.

We understand that your privacy is extremely important to you. As a result we have put in place a number of measures to ensure that any personal data we obtain from you visiting this website is processed and maintained in accordance with accepted principles of good information handling and also in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. This statement provides you with details of the type of information we may hold about you, how we obtain and use any information and how we protect your privacy.

1

| 

OBTAINING INFORMATION  
  
1.1

| 

You are free to browse the website [www.paydayuk.co.uk](https://www.paydayuk.co.uk/ "Home") (the “Website”) without providing any personal information (although, please see the “Cookies” section below).  
  
1.2

| 

We may as a result of your interaction with the Website, including the use of any “Live Chat” facility, store and process your information on our computers, hard copy records and electronic media. By "your information" we mean personal and financial information we (a) obtain from you or from third parties, such as credit reference agencies (CallCredit, Experian, Equifax, who may search the Electoral Register), or fraud prevention agencies when you apply for an account or any other product or service or which you or they give to us at any other time or (b) learn from the way you use and manage your account(s), from your transactions and from the payments made to your account.  
  
1.3

| 

If however you e-mail a question to [account.services@paydaycontact.co.uk](mailto:account.services@paydaycontact.co.uk), or register your interest in our product(s), then it will be necessary for us to collect information about you in order to e-mail a reply or, respond to you.  
  
1.4

| 

The information that we usually collect is as follows:                   

| 

1.4.1

    | 

Directly from you, via our online application form  

Personal information such as:

Name

E-mail address

Home address and residential status

Telephone numbers if provided   

Date of birth

The name and contact details of your employer

Income details, including your pay dates  

Bank account details

Any other information you choose to provide to us through your use of any “LiveChat” facility.    
  
---|---  
  
1.4.2

    | 

From what you do on our site

This can show us for example which elements of the website you use most and least. (See also the Cookies section below)  
  
1.4.3

    | 

From third parties

We may receive personal information from third parties so that we can offer our products and/or services to individuals who have been identified as potentially interested in such products and/or services. We are keen to ensure that any personal information received from third parties is accurate and we aim to check the accuracy of such information from time to time when we have contact with you.  
  
2.

| 

USE OF COLLECTED INFORMATION  
  
2.1

| 

The information we collect about you will be recorded electronically and may be used in the following ways:                                                                                                     

| 

2.1.1

    | 

To verify your identity and credit standing and to enable us to consider and process your application for a loan or other products or services.  
  
---|---  
  
2.1.2

| 

To assess your credit history and confirm your employment details.  
  
2.1.3

| 

To detect, prevent and investigate actual and potential fraud and related activities.  
  
2.1.4   

| 

To collect unpaid loans and debt that may be owed by you to us.  
  
2.1.5

    | 

To develop, manage and market products and services to meet your needs, to contact you for products and services that may be of interest, to determine your eligibility for different products and services that you may be interested in.  
  
2.1.6

| 

To help us to administer and service your account with us.  
  
2.1.7

    | 

To contact you in connection with your enquiry, even if you do not proceed to complete an application with us.  
  
2.1.8

    | 

To extract certain information for the purpose of generating statistics for our own internal purposes (including credit and/or behaviour scoring, and market and product analysis).  
  
2.1.9

| 

To notify you about changes to our service.  
  
2.1.10   

| 

To update our website to better meet our customers’ needs in the future and/or to ensure that the content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer.  
  
2.1.11

    | 

To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.  
  
3.

| 

SHARING YOUR INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES  
  
3.1

| 

We may share your personal information with any member of our group of affiliated companies who may process your personal information for the purposes specified in this privacy policy. For a list of our group of affiliated companies with whom we may share your personal information, please click here. The list of our group of affiliated companies with whom your data may be shared will change from time to time, so please ensure that you revisit this link regularly.  
  
3.2

|                                                        | 

3.2.1

    | 

To provide you with a loan. As brokers as well as direct lenders, our products and services are sometimes provided in conjunction with our business partners. It will therefore be necessary to disclose your information to them to provide you with the products and/or services you require.  
  
---|---  
  
3.2.2

| 

To our agents, staff and approved third parties to carry out services for us.  
  
3.2.3

    | 

To facilitate the processing and collection of direct debits or other payments due from you under the loan agreement, we may also share your personal data with third party payment processing service providers.  
  
3.2.4

    | 

To provide you with information about special promotions and offers as referred to in the “Keeping You Informed” section below.  
  
3.2.5

    | 

To protect us, our group of affiliated companies or others. We may share your information with third parties when we believe it is necessary to comply with the law or protect our or another person's rights, property, or safety. This includes exchanging information with third parties (such as other lenders, law enforcement agencies and regulatory authorities) to protect against fraud and reduce risks.  
  
3.2.6

    | 

If there is (or is to be) any change in ownership of our business or assets then we may wish to share your information so that the new (prospective) owners may continue to operate our business effectively and continue to provide services to our customers. This may include new shareholders or any organisation that might take an assignment or transfer of any agreements we have entered into with our customers.  
  
We will place appropriate obligations and restrictions on third parties to protect your details.  
  
3.3

| 

In some circumstances, your details may be passed to another lender (not necessarily within our group of affiliated companies) who may be able to offer you a payday loan. Please refer to the relevant pages within the loan application process for further information.  
  
4.

| 

CREDIT REFERENCE AND FRAUD PROTECTION AGENCIES  
  
4.1

| 

We may use credit reference and fraud prevention agencies to help us make decisions.  
  
4.2

| 

When you apply to us to open an account, we will check the following records about you and others (see 4.4 below):                  

| 

4.2.1

| 

our own;  
  
---|---  
  
4.2.2

    | 

those at credit reference agencies (CRAs). When CRAs receive a search from us they will place a search footprint on your credit file that may be seen by other lenders. They supply to us both public (including the electoral register) and shared credit and fraud prevention information.  
  
4.2.3

| 

those at fraud prevention agencies (FPAs).  
  
4.3

| 

We will make checks such as assessing this application for credit and verifying identities to prevent and detect crime and money laundering. We may also make periodic searches at CRAs and FPAs in order to refresh our records and manage your account with us, including whether to make credit available or to continue or extend existing credit, focus the relevance of the marketing communications that we send to you, and/or ensure that we comply with our obligations regarding responsible lending.  
  
4.4

| 

If you are making a joint application or tell us that you have a spouse or financial associate, we will link your records together so you must be sure that you have their agreement to disclose information about them. CRAs also link your records together and these links will remain on your and their files until such time as you or your partner successfully files for a disassociation with the CRAs to break that link.  
  
4.5

| 

Information on applications will be sent to CRAs and will be recorded by them. Where you borrow from us, we will give details of your accounts and how you manage it/them to CRAs. If you borrow and do not repay in full and on time, CRAs will record the outstanding debt. This information may be supplied to other organisations by CRAs and FPAs to perform similar checks and to trace your whereabouts and recover debts that you owe. Records remain on file for 6 years after they are closed, whether settled by you or defaulted.  
  
4.6

| 

If you give us false or inaccurate information and we suspect or identify fraud we will record this and may also pass this information to FPAs and other organisations involved in crime and fraud prevention. Law enforcement agencies (such as the police, HMRC and other regulatory bodies) may access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when:

  *   Checking details on applications for credit and credit related or other facilities;
  *   Managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities;
  *   Recovering debt;
  *   Checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance;
  *   Checking details of job applicants and employees.

4.7

| 

If you have borrowed from us and do not make payments that you owe us, we will trace your whereabouts and recover debts.  
  
4.8

| 

We and other organisations may access and use from other countries the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies.  
  
4.9

| 

Your data may also be used for other purposes for which you give your specific permission or, in very limited circumstances, when required by law or where permitted under the terms of the Data Protection Act 1998.  
  
4.10

| 

This section is a condensed explanation of how personal information is used for credit referencing and fraud prevention purposes. If you would like to read the full details of how your credit reference data may be used please refer to “A Guide to the use of your personal information by PaydayUK and at Credit Reference and Fraud Prevention Agencies” by clicking here.  
  
4.11

| 

You can contact the CRAs currently operating in the UK; the information they hold may not be the same so it is worth contacting them all. They will charge you a small statutory fee, currently £2.00.

CallCredit, Consumer Services Team, PO Box 491, Leeds, LS3 1WZ or call 0870 06014141

Equifax PLC, Credit File Advice Centre, PO Box 3001, Bradford, BD1 5US or call 0870 010 05831 or log on to [www.myequifax.co.uk](http://www.myequifax.co.uk/)

Experian, Consumer Help Service, PO Box 8000, Nottingham NG80 7WF or   call 0844 48180001 or log on to [www.experian.co.uk](http://www.experian.co.uk/)  
  
4.12

| 

Please contact our Data Protection Officer (see “Contact Our Data Protection Officer” below) if you want to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies.  
  
5.

| 

USE OF YOUR INFORMATION OUTSIDE OF THE UK  
  
5.1

| 

Some companies within our group of affiliated companies, and sometimes other third parties with whom we share personal information are or may be located outside the UK; for example, Dollar Financial Group Inc. is located in the USA. We implement safeguards within our group of affiliated companies and with relevant third parties to ensure the appropriate levels of protection for all such information.  
  
6.

| 

METHODS OF CONTACT

Unless you have advised us to the contrary, both we and any other broker, lender or third party referred to above may contact you by telephone, SMS, post, e-mail or fax. (Please see the ‘Keeping You Informed’ section below regarding how you may be contacted for direct marketing purposes).  
  
7.

| 

HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION?

Unless you have advised us to the contrary, we and any other broker, lender or third party referred to above may contact you by telephone, SMS, post, e-mail or fax. (Please see the ‘Keeping You Informed’ section below regarding how you may be contacted for direct marketing purposes).  
  
7.1

| 

How long we keep your information for depends on the basis on which it was provided, generally however:                                 

| 

7.1.1

    | 

We will keep the information that is necessary to enable us to provide you with a service that you have requested through this website for as long as it takes us to provide that service.  
  
---|---  
  
7.1.2

    | 

If you have asked that we do not use your details for marketing purposes, we may still need to keep them to ensure our systems reflect your preferences.     
  
7.1.3

    | 

We will generally keep records of any transactions you enter into on this website for a minimum of six years from the end of the relationship. This is so that we can respond to any complaints or disputes that arise in that period. Otherwise we will keep the information where appropriate for legitimate business needs.  
  
7.1.4

    | 

We will keep other information about you if it is necessary for us to do so to comply with the law, or where appropriate for legitimate business needs.  
  
8.

| 

KEEPING YOU INFORMED  
  
8.1

| 

From time to time we would like to contact you by SMS, post, email, telephone or automated message, with offers relating to products of ours which we think you might be interested in.  
  
8.2

| 

We may also wish to share some of your information (including all the contact details that we hold for you) with trusted third parties so that they can also provide you with information (using the same methods to contact you) about products and services that might be of interest to you. One of the reasons that we wish to share your data with such third parties, including the application details you have already provided, is that they may be able to offer you a loan in the event that you are unsuccessful in obtaining a loan from PaydayUK. One of our third party intermediaries will then consider your details and may forward these details to another lender, which may involve them completing a further credit check. You will be contacted by any lender who may have considered your application to advise you if your application has been unsuccessful. Other intermediaries and lenders will have their own privacy policies. Please refer to them.  
  
8.3

| 

When you submit your application, you will be asked to agree to the use of your information in clause 8 above.  
  
9.

| 

ACCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION WE HOLD ABOUT YOU  
  
9.1

| 

Subject to certain exceptions, you have the right of access to your personal records and information that we hold about you, upon written request and payment of a charge of up to £10. You will need to make a separate request and pay a separate fee for each company within our group of affiliated companies whose records you wish to access.  
  
10.

| 

UPDATE YOUR DETAILS/PREFERENCES  
  
10.1

| 

If any data or information we hold about you is inaccurate or out of date then please let us know and this will be corrected where appropriate.  
  
10.2

| 

To revise your marketing contact preferences, or to access, correct or amend your records you should contact the Data Protection Officer (see “Contact Our Data Protection Officer” below).  
  
11.

| 

SECURITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY  
  
11.1

| 

Appreciating that both privacy and security of your information is of the utmost importance, we have implemented technology and security policies, rules and measures to protect the personal information we hold about you.  
  
11.2

| 

We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information. However, please be aware that there are inherent security risks of providing information and dealing online over the internet and we cannot   therefore guarantee the security of any data disclosed online. We ask that you do not provide us with any sensitive personal information online (please   see the ‘Sensitive Information’ Section below) unless we specifically ask for this.  
  
12.

| 

COOKIES  
  
12.1

| 

Use of Cookies                           

| 

12.1.1

    | 

We use cookies to help us analyse traffic on our site and customer behaviour. Cookies may also be used by our partners to understand marketing and traffic patterns. During the course of any visit to Payday Express, the pages you see, along with a cookie, are downloaded to your computer. Any information that is supplied by cookies can help us to provide you with a better service and assists us in analysing the profile of our visitors.  
  
---|---  
  
12.1.2

    | 

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but normally you can alter your browser settings to prevent automatic acceptance, if you prefer. If you decline cookies, we cannot guarantee that     your experience with our website will be as quick or responsive as if you do receive cookies.  
  
12.1.3

    | 

We do not store passwords or any other information about a visitor in a cookie that could identify them, their location, their preferences or their financial activity.  
  
12.1.4

    | 

We use aggregated customer information to help us understand how our website is performing commercially and what we can do to improve performance. We may provide this information to other companies, such as third party advertisers. This information does NOT include any personal details that can be used to identify individuals.  
  
If you do not want to receive cookies from us, please follow the procedures below. These procedures do not apply to cookies sent by our business partners.  
  
12.2

| 

Cookies Used by PaydayUK               

| 

"389303980-source"

| 

Contains the affiliate that introduced the user to our site.  
  
---|---  
  
"389303980-sourcerecent"

| 

Contains a collated 30 day list of affiliates that introduced the user to our site, with an attached date stamp.  
  
Announcements

| 

Contains a variable time based cookie detailing if a user has previously seen the PaydayUK announcement banner, preventing it being continuously displayed.  
  
Google Display and remarketing

| 

Google employ display and remarketing tracking, which can result in third party vendors such as Google displaying our adverts on sites across the internet. You can opt out of these using Google's [Ads settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads?hl=en&sig=ACi0TChLGGoN2PjtmLDo-z1bPxDOm7o8mLOqgjJlEAQuFCljeB8SPJ95DRnOnXFPSoWqETNdZc4Ccrdn6Ar5vTfz6Vk2TwgBHb61hhbbe2IJYGp-pDMc2bjG2Vt1tlcJvQRXK8UF25V6vtfgNSsdAE68keIVsAsdG9HnjND_gIA3WUP7GjAHpskUHIRmy3cPAhT1AAgNyFNDE60q93mmtQcozssLGCCwEQ "Google Ad Settings") page  
  
12.3

| 

Cookies Used by Third Party Advertisers

We also work with 3rd party advertisers that use various technologies to serve advertisements when you visit our website and other sites on which we advertise. In the course of serving these advertisements, a unique   third-party cookie may be placed or recognized on your browser.

These cookies are used to gather non-personally identifiable information about visits to our website and the sites upon which we advertise (not including your name, address, or any other personal information).

These type of cookies may be used for the following purposes:

To show relevant advertisements on other websites

To show relevant advertisements based on your prior visit to our website

Measure the performance of our online advertising

In terms of tracking we work with the following partners:

  *   Google / Doubleclick
  *   Unanimis
  *   MediaIQ
  *   Quantcast

You can find out more about the use of cookies and opt out any time via the following links:

Google & Associated Services  
  <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences>

Other 3rd Party Advertisers   
  UK - <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/>   
  US - <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>  
  
12.4

| 

How to Find and Control Your Cookies                                        

| 

12.4.1

    | 

If you're using Internet Explorer 6.0, 7.0, 8.0 or 9.0:   

Choose Tools, then: 

Internet Options   

Click the Privacy tab  

Click on the 'Advanced' button   

Check the 'Override automatic cookie handing' box and select Accept, Block or Prompt for action as appropriate.  
  
---|---  
  
12.4.2

    | 

If you're using Mozilla Firefox:  

Choose Tools, then:   

Options... 

Privacy  

Cookies

Set your options as required  
  
12.4.3

    | 

If you're using Opera 8+:

Choose Tools, then

Preferences

Advanced

Select Cookies

Select your settings using the available options  
  
12.4.4

    | 

If you're using Safari:

Choose Safari, then

Preferences 

Security 

Select options by Accept Cookies as required.  
  
12.5

| 

How do you know which of the sites you've visited use cookies?                               

| 

12.5.1

    | 

If you're using Internet Explorer: 

Choose Tools, then 

Internet Options

Click the General tab

Click Settings

View Files.  
  
---|---  
  
12.5.2

    | 

If you're using Mozilla Firefox:

Choose Tools, then 

Options...

Privacy

Cookies

Click the Show Cookies button.  
  
12.5.3

    | 

If you're using Opera 8+:

Choose Tools, then

Advanced

Click Cookies.  
  
12.5.4

    | 

If you're using Safari:

Choose Safari, then

Preferences

Security

Click Show Cookies button.   
  
12.6

| 

How to see your cookie code

Just click on a cookie to open it. You'll see a short string of text and numbers. The numbers are your identification card, which can only be seen by the server that gave you the cookie.  
  
12.7

| 

Further Information About Cookies

The [Interactive Advertising Bureau](http://www.iab.net/) is an industry body that has produced a series of web pages which explain how cookies work and how they can be managed.  
  
12.8

| 

Third Party Web Beacons

We use third party web beacons from Yahoo! to help analyse where visitors go and what they do while visiting our website. Yahoo! may also use anonymous information about your visits to this and other websites in order to improve its products and services and provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by Yahoo! click [here](https://reports.web.analytics.yahoo.com/optout,OptOut.vm).  
  
13.

| 

LINKS TO OTHER SITES

This website may from time to time include links to other sites. We make   every effort to provide links to high quality, reputable sites but we're not   responsible for their privacy practices or, site content, or the services they offer. Please always check the privacy policies of any linked sites.  
  
14.

| 

SENSITIVE INFORMATION

Information about you which is considered sensitive information under the Data Protection Act 1998, includes information about your medical or health conditions, racial or ethnic origin, political opinions or trade union membership, religious or philosophical beliefs and sexual orientation, and suspected or proven criminal activity and related proceedings. If we need to process sensitive personal data, you will be notified of such processing and asked to specifically agree to the use of such information as appropriate.  
  
15.

| 

TELEPHONE CALLS

If you call any of the telephone numbers quoted on this website, in our literature or in correspondence, we may record your call. These recordings are used for training, regulatory and quality control purposes to ensure that we continuously monitor and improve our customer service standards.  
  
16.

| 

WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS

This policy only applies to personal information collected or obtained by us.  
  
17.

| 

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

We may amend this privacy policy from time to time. If any amendments are made then a notice will be posted on this website. This privacy policy was last updated on 1 March 2012.  
  
18.

| 

CONTACT OUR DATA PROTECTION OFFICER  
  
18.1

| 

Should you have any queries or require any information about this privacy policy then these should be directed to the Data Protection Officer:

By email at [account.services@paydaycontact.co.uk](mailto:account.services@paydaycontact.co.uk)

By post at PaydayUK, PO Box 255, Bicester, Oxfordshire, OX26 4ZY.
